Going out again?
Don't forget, we're going to Grandma's tomorrow.
I-I know.
Hey, Mom?
Dad's alive, right?
This again? Yes, he's alive, I told you already!
I know, but...
I've only ever spoken to him through our lawyers.
But, I can tell you he pays his child support.
So much that I thought about sending it back.
Wait, really?!
Sorry. I was being stubborn about
it and didn't want to tell you.
I was young,
and wanted to say
I'd raised you all on my own,
so I never touched the money.
I kept it all for you, of course.
I thought if you started to resent him,
I'd step in and tell you about it.
But you still love him, don't you?
You never stopped wearing
that cute hairpin, after all.
Oh.
I just...
Y'know, Mom...
Dad still draws manga.
Really? Did you talk to him?
No, I didn't, but...
You don't have to tell me, but...
Is he working on something he likes?
If you see him, could you tell him something?
I will.
The Protagonist's Story
Holy shit!
This is crazy!
My feed is literally nothing
but the Angelic Airborne!
Whoa, damn!
They're so pretty!
I can't even begin to describe how this makes me feel.
C'mon, Sensei, you gotta see this!
Wow, that's incredible.
Liliel looks exactly like how
Takamatsu-sensei draws her.
Don't be like that!
Look, they've got an Ariel!
You're right. She looks good, too.
Sensei, your art! No!
W-was her cosplay that good?
Ten years. It's been ten whole years!
No, it has to be her.
She looks just like her
mother back when we first met.
But, why?
Mita-kun.
Could I make it to Comiket in time from here?
Wait, you want to actually go?
You could, but then we'll
definitely miss our deadline!
I have to go now,
or I'll never be
the man I should have been!
How could I ever have chosen work over family?
What kind of man does that?!
But, I can't...
Wait, what?
Okay, it's up to us to get this inked!
I was just getting bored of backgrounds, anyway.
Dunno why you gotta jet, but go! We've got this.
We all know how to draw everything in your style.
Come help, Mita!
Go, Sensei! We'll manage this without you!
Thank you so much.
We're taking a ten-minute break!
Our crowd is sticking around!
Yeah! What a difference from yesterday!
Why are you surprised? We rehearsed like crazy.
There's no way she knows I work on the manga.
It must be some kind of divine punishment,
or miraculous coincidence...
Where do I go now?
Mita-kun?!
Sensei, they're on the roof!
Go to the top of the West Exhibition Hall!
Thank you!
I've been drawing shonen manga for a decade now.
Telling my readers, "be kind," "be a good example,"
but that all counts for nothing if
I can't live up to those same ideals!
So many people...
Liliel-chan!
Over here!
Wait, all these people are here to see them?!
People are shouting the names
of characters I draw all the time.
This is weird.
Mikarin!
Wait, I don't have a Mikarin!
Ariel!
Oh, Aria. Look how you've grown.
I hate you, and I hate your stupid manga!
I lost myself in my work,
and broke my daughter's heart...
But manga was the only way I knew how to survive.
Did my absence leave a permanent scar?
She must hate me, and manga, too.
Manga hurt the people I loved the most,
yet I'm still choosing it over them.
I'm a monster.
Ariel is so fun and energetic.
Is she based on someone?
Uh, no?
I was a horrible person who'd never redeem himself.
Yet there I was,
writing stories about the most good,
moral characters.
I wanted people to live like this.
Fan Letters
I wanted to live like this.
I didn't care if that sentiment changed anyone.
I didn't.
I didn't care.
No.
There's no way she knows
I'm the author of Side Story.
It's a coincidence.
I always wanted to know how she felt,
but even if I had the courage to ask her now,
it would only end up hurting her again.
I know she's a good kid.
Her mother would've raised her well.
Don't assume this means she forgives you.
I'll never stop paying for my mistakes.
We're taking a ten-minute break!
Ink and calluses? Like a manga-ka?
No, come on.
Senpai!
How're you all feeling?
I'm feeling great!
Want some water?
Dad?
Kisaki-sensei is here?!
Then I was right!
Aria-chan!
Let's go.
Wait, where are you going? He went that way!
Senpai, can you buy us some time?!
Because...
Wait, is there time?!
We also made a VB Melia costume!
And it's super high-quality!
We want him to see it!
Okay!
Higarashi-sensei!
Yes! Tomorrow's the deadline, I know!
JOLT
SHUDDER SHUDDER
Wait, my editor's definitely not here, so...
Do I know you?
I'm, uh... I'm a huge Liliel otaku!
I can see that!
They only ever made ten of those hats!
How did you know it was me?
I dunno, I...
Just kinda guessed from your appearance?
Could...
Could I get your autograph?!
Yes, of course.
You're the best!
Wait, this is rare merch.
I'm not the real deal.
You should get Takamatsu-sensei's
autograph instead.
I can get him to sign it for you.
No, I want your autograph, Higarashi-sensei.
Don't say you're not the real deal.
I've been reading Side Story
religiously for ten years.
Right. Okay, then...
Higarashi
Thank you so much!
It's nothing, really. Thank you for being a fan.
I should get going. I've got a deadline to hit.
Wait, uh...
I hate to be that guy,
but could you also draw something for me?
Like Liliel!
I mean, sure, but... You really want me to?
Yes, please!
I'm terrible at doing quick sketches...
Let me start the eyes here, I guess?
You can take your time, I don't mind!
Okay, then I'll be extra careful.
Th-that's not what I meant, but sure!
There.
I'll treasure this forever.
He drew that so fast!
Shit! He's so gonna hit me
with the "if that's all" now!
Hurry up, Liliel!
If that's all, then...
Here goes nothing!
I also loved Valkyrie Battle!
Wait, do people know that was me?!
I knew it!
No, I just had a hunch.
And you just tricked me into confirming it...
Thank you, though.
I didn't think it had any fans.
My first Jump magazine was
the one with its debut,
and I followed it religiously!
I thought it was so cool that Melia got
wings when she used her special attack!
I thought girls with wings were so hot!
So y'know, when I finally got into
The Ashford Chronicles,
that's probably why I fell so hard for Liliel!
Is that right?
I shouldn't have brought up the Ashford Chronicles!
Sorry, I didn't mean it like that!
No, I-I should apologize.
That crap was a dark stain on my life.
Hearing about the story or its
characters brings back all that trauma.
It still hurts.
I know better than anyone how terrible it was,
but it was all I could do back then.
So please, I really wish you wouldn't
call yourself a fan of that schlock.
I'm sorry I have to tell you this. I really am.
But please, I just want to forget it exists.
How can he say that?
I mean, I can't imagine how he must feel, but still...
Thank you for your letter,
Okumura-kun. But please don't tell your
friends you like my manga.
They'll make fun of you.
That's so wrong!
Aria is putting on her Melia costume!
If she shows up now, it'll be a disaster!
Should I stop her? No, that'd be worse!
Ririsa, Aria, I'm sorry...
This isn't about buying time anymore.
This is about my story now!
Stop it.
Don't call it crap.
You have no right to badmouth your work.
Kids aren't their parents' property.
Your work doesn't belong to you.
It doesn't belong to us readers, either.
It's a world of its own!
No one can tell anyone
how to feel about something.
And no matter what you say about it, Sensei,
I will always love that manga.
Even if you want to forget it, I won't!
to Kisaki-sensei
from Okumura
Okumura-kun? Is that you?
Why is it schlock?
Because it had haters?
Name a single manga without haters! Go on!
What makes you a fake?
Because you work on the spin-off?
Do you think those cosplays were fake,
then, because they weren't the 'real deal'?
No, I'd never...
Fine, you want me to spell it out for you, then?!
I don't give a shit about what the author thinks!
You want facts?! I'll hit you with the facts!
Back then, I loved him with my whole heart.
That fact will never change.
The manga you made,
the manga you created, made me happy!
I don't care if you're the author,
you can't change the fact that it changed my life!
For ten years, I've lived in absolute misery.
office
(open immediately)
It's getting cancelled, Kisaki-sensei.
Try and wrap it up in five chapters.
We'll bundle it into two volumes, so we'll need...
I was so relieved.
I knew I couldn't keep going with it.
One day, I'm gonna make her the
main character of her own story!
You'll get to read it first!
Okay, honey.
I loved drawing Melia. I loved her so much.
I always wished I'd never created her.
But, no parent ever wishes their
daughter had never been born.
I never could have imagined...
...that Melia was bringing
someone out there so much happiness.
No... I pretended it was impossible.
I knew there were people who said they loved it,
but I couldn't bring myself to believe it.
JUMP New Author Contest Winners
Runner-Up: Coming to Jump!
I wanted my manga in Weekly Shonen Jump,
wanted it to reach the hearts of a million readers.
But I couldn't make one person happy.
I couldn't fathom how incredible that would be.
Forgive me, Aria.
Forgive me for prioritizing the feelings of
a million readers over your happiness.
Forgive me, Melia.
Your heart was far more righteous than mine.
I should never have despised you.
You, too, were my beloved daughter.
I beg of you, please, forgive me. Please.
Dad.
M-Melia...
Aria?
W-why?
Can't you tell? Isn't it obvious how I feel?
I'm sorry! I'm so sorry!
I'm sorry, too.
Okumura said most of what I wanted to say.
Can we be good now?
I know it's been ten years.
Yes.
My hands are so dirty, though.
I won't yell at you.
Mom's the only one who had to
deal with my rebellious phase.
Oh... I'm sorry.
Could you stop apologizing?
Kids get mad at their parents for
ignoring them, or nagging them,
or fighting with them,
or disappearing on them...
Sometimes, we might even say we hate them.
But do you think any kid really
wants to hate their mom or dad?
I'm your daughter. I know how Melia must feel.
That's why we're both here right now.
Listen close, because we're only
going to say this once, okay?
Thank you for bringing me into this world.
I'm the one who should be thanking you.
Aria, Melia...
Thank you for coming into this world.
Uh-huh.
I never thought I'd get to meet you in real life.
It took ten years...
But, today is finally a good day.
Side Story has given so much
more character development to Liliel!
Uh-huh.
Just by having her go from side to main character,
she now has to be the one dealing with conflict
and overcoming her own obstacles!
Do you want to talk to your Dad?
Honestly? I don't know what I'd say.
I'm kinda glad Ririsa is doing her thing.
How does she have more to say
to him than his literal daughter?
He might be Aria's dad,
but to Ririsa and I, he's a god.
Here you all go.
Thank you so much!
I'm so glad I brought shikishi boards
just in case we ran into him!
You're a genius!
I should be thanking you.
Thank you for cosplaying from Liliel: Side Story.
I'm so happy to have met passionate fans like you.
Which makes this next part hard to tell you.
Liliel: Side Story is due to end soon.
What?! It's getting canceled? But it got an anime!
Is it not selling well?
It's selling, but it's not growing.
It's not losing money,
but it's been going on for a while,
so the Editorial team said
I can end it whenever I want.
So you're thinking about ending the story?
Wait, are you sure you should be telling us all this?
Yes, because I've decided not to end it.
It was hard to stay passionate about the
series when it was all about the stale sales.
But today, I got to see the joy on the faces
of people who read and buy the manga.
I've got to keep going, if only for you.
Wait, so...
Editorial won't get on my case
if the sales are still okay.
I'm not sure what I can do to improve them, but...
You still won't look at them?
It's Takamatsu-sensei's work.
I'm just the fake replacement.
Liliel: Side Story is my manga.
It'll end if I stop working on it.
They said I can end it whenever I want.
Might as well keep going
until they decide to fire me.
I can promise you that.
It's thanks to you that I discovered this joy again.
You and your wonderful Airborne Squadron cosplays.
And you've rescued me a second time, Okumura-kun.
Wait, what?
to Kisaki-sensei
from Okumura
It's nothing special. It's just what otaku do.
I should get going.
Tonight's my deadline.
If I miss it, they might actually fire me.
Oh, yikes!
Then please, hurry back!
Okay, Aria...
Yeah.
You're still wearing that hairpin.
You remember it?
Of course I do. It's special.
I remember why your mother bought it, too.
I look just like Melia!
I saw it at the store and knew it
would make you and Daddy happy.
Daddy won't come out of his office.
Yeah, we're fighting.
I totally forgot about it while I was at the store.
I'm so silly.
Daddy says he wants to talk!
I'm sorry.
No, I'm sorry...
I always took special care of it.
I always wore it, too.
It's the hairpin that brought
you and Mom back together.
I suppose that's right.
Oh, Dad.
Mom wanted me to tell you something.
She did?
Whatcha drawing?
I, uh...
Damn, that's so good!
It is?
Has no one told you?
I haven't shown this to anyone yet.
That makes me your first reader!
Makes me special, huh?
What did she say?
I mean, I don't really understand what it meant, but...
Promise me I'll be the first reader on your next manga.
Okay.
I was happy then, and happy now.
Back then, I loved him with my whole heart.
That fact will never change.
I promise.
This Wonderful World